All right, guys. So a couple of
weeks ago, we actually interviewed a public CEO,
Mark White of Nexalyn Technologies.
Because I actually am the CEO of a
public company and I run my own business.
I'm in the business of
getting people off psychiatric medication
and using frequencies to restore mental health
so that life on life's terms
is a pleasure rather than a struggle.
He actually invited us out
to his headquarters in Houston, Texas,
to give us some more game for young entrepreneurs.
In this interview, Mark revealed to
us some of the greatest business lessons
that he's learned that have enabled him to
become a CEO of a publicly traded company.
I'm James Newman, and this is Questions with Millionaires.
What was that first business that you ever started?
Car detailing.
You know, I was a valet parker at a
hotel here in Houston back in the oil boom.
So we're in the late 70s now.
And I was parking cars at a hotel,
what was one of the
original Western four-star hotels in Houston
at what was the new Galleria at that time.
And people would drive their car.
To the hotel and then go in for dinner
because back then a lot of
the nice restaurants were in the hotels.
And while they were at dinner, I got the idea.
Everybody remember Armor All?
Well, Armor All was brand new.
And the idea of cleaning a
wheel and Armor Alling a tire
made a car look brand new.
And the doorman and myself got this
idea that while people go in for dinner,
we would take the car and
say, listen, while you're in for dinner,
Can we go in for dinner?
Why don't we come over tonight?
wash and detail your car. And they would go,
what do you mean? Say $20 and we'll show you
what a detail on a car would look
like. And that created what was called extraordinary detail.
And so I would park cars at night and in
the mornings I would go pick up cars, Lincoln Mark
Fives and Cadillac Eldorados. Those were the
cars just before all the foreign car
booms. And I would pick up the car at their
office and I'd take it to my house and I'd take
a toothbrush to the wheels and I'd armor all the
tires. And that was it. That was my first business.
That was my first big claim to fame. I'm curious
to kind of get your take on sales. You've spent
years studying the brain and psychology.
And obviously psychology is a massive component
of sales. A lot of people will say,
what's been your secret to sales throughout your
career as an entrepreneur? Boy, you know, I used
to do the, in my day, the Zig Ziglar
school, sales school. And for some of
your older viewers, followers, they'll remember the
Zig Ziglar. And I used to do the Zig
Ziglar school, sales school. And for some of your
older viewers, followers, they'll remember the Zig Ziglar.
And then of course, there's the Tony Robbins.
I happen to be blessed with a lot of energy
and a lot of confidence. Okay. And I have learned how
to communicate. Okay. Because really, yeah, we can
talk about psychology and we can talk about
teaching someone how to close the sale, ask for
the deal. That's not my, that's not my type of
selling. I communicate with people. And there are a
lot of people that I've met that have done
that. And I've had a lot of really
successful salesmen that are not salesmen or saleswomen.
They're just great communicators and they really
love their product or love their service. They're
very passionate about it and they believe in it. And
like when you sit with me and you talk about
Nexulin technology, or you talk about unique
mind care, you talk about brain training,
brain stimulation, very quickly, you'll see that I really
love what I do. Okay. That is a natural
sales moment.
Because you want to know, because that's natural
human curiosity, what's driving me to be so
positive and upbeat. And what I do is,
is in a sales scenario is most importantly,
when I walk into a room, one of the
first thing I think is, why would they say no?
Why would they turn me away? Why would they not
want to listen to what I have? And the first thing
I'm going to do when I walk in
that room is I'm going to start asking questions.
And I'm going to listen to the response. And
as I'm listening to the response, I'm tailoring my
message that I'm there to talk about whatever it
may be, because that's how I'm able to meet their
needs. And by listening to them, I'm respecting them.
And I can engage with them in a way that
interests them. And more importantly, I don't tell
them something that they don't want to know.
Or the opposite would be tell
them something that they already know,
and they know better than I do. So when
I do some presentations in a room of 30 people,
you know, the first thing I'll say is,
how many medical professionals are in the room?
And usually there's going to be a hand or two
that goes up. And the first thing I'm going to
try to do, as I said earlier, I'm going to
show some humility. I'm not going to try to pretend
that I know healthcare better than they know
healthcare. I'm simply here to offer a vision
of what I think could
be a better health care system.
Exactly.
And research really has the ability to
help people from them know what's actually been
the best best for the health
system, the better for the health quality.
So anyway, so you really never go around failing to
sit around doing anything for the best.
You never do that.
You have to keep on going.
Messenger was like, I've never
been in this situation before.
It's what it is, Viender.
Let's have a look.
It's like a Silicon Valleyrik exam.
So why not that?
I think that, that's programming.
That's the real problem.
You have a lot of technology.
And many have your stuff.
And many other professionals in this organization.
I've had positive experience withippleWellness.
up, and we've managed to looking out of so
many different recent experiences when I'm up at the
I like to communicate. I'm a talker. That's my nature.
Wow. That was a great answer. Yeah, it was.
What would you say is the best
advice that you ever received from a mentor?
Talk too much. Talk too much. Slow down. Slow
down. Say what you're going to say in fewer words
because the people that you're speaking to don't
know it as well as you know it.
Okay, that's one. Obviously, another one that
I mentioned in our first interview is finance,
money. You know, money, you got to be
really careful how you fund your businesses and how
you spend your money both in your personal
life and your professional life because in the
entrepreneurial world, they come together. You know, you
have a big week in your company. It's
Friday and you've done a few thousand dollars
worth of business and suddenly you're in Saks Fifth
Avenue buying a suit or you're in
a restaurant buying a $200 bottle of wine.
Trust me, I've been through all of this and this is
why I say, be careful. Don't let it go to your
head. And I will tell you another thing, another
really powerful lesson that I learned, not from a
mentor, humility. That is by far one of the
most important character traits of, and I'd like to
think of my professional life. I'm confident and
I'm aggressive, but I have a lot of humility
because I try to always be aware of what I
don't know and always think about what I don't know.
Always be aware of what I don't know. And I'm
a professional, but I try to always be aware of what
I don't know and always think about what I
don't know. And I'm a professional, but I'm a professional,
share what I do know in a positive and uplifting
way so that I can share it with others in the
form of wisdom, you know, because knowledge and
wisdom is what it's about. And knowledge is,
you know, firsthand experience and wisdom
comes from listening to those with knowledge.
And I like to play in both circles. Yeah.
So an interesting thing that I've always thought about
kind of growing up in my generation, there's
an individual who might be controversial to some
people, you know, there's a documentary on him,
Kanye West, music artist. So throughout his life,
you see he had a very close relationship
with his mother. And then pretty much everything from
there on out, his life is very like
this, but controversial stuff in the news, you know,
people are really concerned about his mental
health. He was taking medications as well,
probably on a lot of different medications. You
saw some weight gain there, stuff like that.
I'm curious to know your thoughts of
how does a traumatic event like, you know,
not necessarily head injury, but like,
the loss of a relationship, like the
more relationship type trauma, how does that affect
the brain? Okay. Trauma. So when I
do presentations, I do some public speaking.
And one of the first words that I talk
about or help educate everybody is the word trauma.
And I said it earlier, you know, it's
it basically, if you actually look up the definition,
most people think trauma is just a major
event with this major injury. No, it's anything,
that is abnormal in the day to day life
experience. All right. So trauma comes in many shapes,
many forms, many styles, but primarily
you have toxic trauma, addiction, alcohol, drugs,
food sensitivity, poisons. Okay. You
have physical trauma, football injuries,
fall off my bicycle, hit my head,
basketball court, you know, traumatic brain injury,
the veterans in the war. Okay. And you have
emotional trauma. All right. Loss of a loved one,
betrayal by a loved one, et cetera. As
we know, some people, as I said, are bulletproof,
not much affects them. They just, they just carry on.
But for some, a little bit of trauma can be
devastating to the brain. The brain has two
systems. It's an electrical system and a chemical
system. And you put the two together and it's,
there's a dance that the two systems do. Okay.
And their job, that their responsibility,
the brain's responsibility with these two systems
is to help them. And so trauma can be devastating
to the brain. And so trauma can be devastating to
the brain. And so trauma can be devastating to
life on life's terms. And what happens in
a traumatic scenario, there is such an overwhelming
response to the trauma, whether it's a little bit
of trauma every day or one day with a major
amount of trauma, your brain has a responsibility to
protect you. And it's the old fight or flight
response. Okay. And it does a very good job
in the moment of protecting you and saving your life.
Unfortunately, for different sets of circumstances
that we would be here all
day discussing,
there are times that the brain
is basically so affected by this
traumatic event, in this case, Kanye losing his mother,
the stabilizing force of his life,
for a man that had a propensity
to be somewhat unstable at different times.
But he has a level of genius
as well and it's not uncommon for some of those
geniuses to have this instability. But my point is,
you have this very stabilizing relationship, this
very intimate, loving, caring relationship
that depends on this mother.
She represents home, she represents security,
she represents intimacy, she's everything
to him. And that loss is so extreme
that in that moment you
get an imbalance in that system.
And unfortunately, as the brain is very good
in the instantaneous moment, sometimes it's not very good
once the trauma is over.
This is where we talk about
PTSD. Most people think PTSD
is always military. Okay, post trauma.
There's that word stress disorder. So after the trauma,
I have a stress disorder. Okay, it's not just Veterans!
You have PTSD from a bad marriage, bad employer
or in this case you can have
PTSD that can manifest in some very unusual ways
with the loss of a loved one. How does that
manifest in a brain? Different brains respond in
different ways. In our world, it's one or both
of those two systems. It's either
a chemical imbalance, dopamine, serotonin, acetylcholine,
these are all the hormones of the brain, okay? Or
it's going to be in the EEG, the frequencies of
the brain, and then where in the brain the trauma
is. And this is what we're in the business of
doing down at the end of the hall. And
this is what, with all fairness to doctors and psychiatrists,
sometimes it's a bit of a guessing game. I'm
here, I feel depressed, I'm losing my, you know,
desire in life, and my marriage is not very
good anymore. And he says, okay, Prozac, let's try that.
And away you go. And
what they're doing is trying to
chemically alter a chemically altered brain, expecting it
to be normal. And it may work some
of the time, but it doesn't work all the time.
It doesn't work most of the time. And this is what
happens to all of us in any type of a
scenario with any type of trauma. And depending on how
your general health and wellness, depending on
what quality of life you currently have,
will determine what response to
certain treatments that you'll have.
But treatment should always begin, in
my humble opinion, with non-invasive technologies,
improvements in nutrition. I do believe in
talk therapy, although some don't, but, you know,
talking to a friend, but basically the foundation of
life. I also happen to be a man of faith,
so I believe in belonging to a spiritual
community as well. And once you start replacing
these opportunities in life to enhance or
destabilize your health, you'll see an improvement. You
won't see it overnight like it is when you
start taking, like if you're struggling from stress
and you take Xanax and suddenly you don't
care about anything except, you know, no longer,
you no longer feel stressed, but you, again,
you've got a whole new set of problems. But
my point is, is that sometimes you don't get somewhere
overnight and you don't get out of it overnight.
You know, it's like weight gain. You know, you
didn't gain a hundred pounds overnight and you're
not going to lose a hundred pounds overnight.
You're going to lose a hundred pounds in
three months. Okay. It's, it's all balanced in life.
So that's kind of where I am on
trauma and the brain and, and restoring brain health.
That's amazing. You've started companies
throughout your entire career. You've brought
a company public. What is the
greatest accomplishment you've had throughout your career?
Getting up, brushing myself off, licking my
wounds and going back in for another round.
I can tell you,
that, you know, you know what the worst thing
of never having money is having a lot of money
and losing it and not having any money. Okay.
And so I'm going to say that the greatest
accomplishment and the greatest success for me is,
is when I've watched at that point in life,
my life's work get loaded up into trucks and
taken down the road. And I had a bankruptcy attorney
that was awesome. His name was
Nelson Hemsley. This guy was spectacular.
And he said, I'm going to go to the bank and I'm going
to go to the bank and I'm going to go to the bank.
And he said to me one day, he said, look, Mark, he said, you can
pay me and I'll go to court and I'll clean up the mess you've made.
And you can go do whatever it is you do and go back
to wherever you came from. Or you can come with me to every meeting
and you can come to me to that courthouse and face the
people that you owe money to. And I'll teach you more about business
and more about life than you ever could
imagine. And you'll ever learn in school, in business,
whatever level of success you've ever had. I will
tell you something. That man gave me a gift.
Truer words have never been spoken. And my
greatest accomplishment was having the strength and the nerve
to go into a room of people that hated me because
I unfortunately failed and I owed them money and they lost money.
And so the greatest accomplishment was to go in
there and do the best I could to apologize,
except that's not really a favor.
I'm not going to say that I'm not a fair
word because I won't tell you that I apologized to them.
But to be in an apologetic space, to give everything I
had back and they had to divvy it up and sell it.
And it is a brutal experience. But on the
other side of it, I was a new man.
I had a new level of respect for my fellow man. I was
divorced at the time. I remarried my wife and put my family back together.
I learned about my family. I learned about my family. I learned
about my family. I learned about my family. I learned about my family.
Humility.
And that is by far in life my greatest accomplishment.
Wow. Are you a reader by any chance?
I'm not.
You're not a reader.
I'm a skimmer.
You're a skimmer. Let me ask you this. What
is your best self-improvement advice for people out there?
For you personally, maybe it's part of your routine.
People, you know, let's just talk
about the average modern man, right?
They're out of shape. They're
addicted to Netflix and dopamine.
What's your advice to people who are
trying to really get their life back?
They want to get on the right track. They're trying
to get serious about becoming maybe financially free and just overall.
Okay. Structure. Okay? Structure.
For instance, I love stories. You
know, I talk about knowledge and wisdom.
And I love taking some of my experiences
of life and applying it to life's wisdom. Okay?
I was in a situation one time and I was working
with this man and his name was Haas of all names.
And I was talking to Haas
and I was asking his advice.
And Haas said, look, this is
what I want you to do.
He said, I want you to
set your alarm for 8 a.m.
Get out of bed. Make your bed. Okay?
Before you leave your room, get
out of bed, make your bed.
Then go take your shower. Okay?
And be ready to go at whatever
you're going to do at 9 a.m.
Eat lunch at noon.
Eat dinner at six.
And after dinner, do, you know, whatever you
need to do for your personal fruit and vegetable.
Okay?
Haas said, look, this is
what I want you to do.
time and be ready to go to bed at nine,
start getting prepared for bed and get in bed at
And I'm like, that's it?
He goes, that's it.
And I'm like, why?
And he said, because you
need to be successful at something.
You just need to do one
thing and be successful at it.
And what will happen is you're going to get bit.
You're going to suddenly feel at the end of
the first day, you're going to go, wow, I
did what I said I was going to do.
I did what I set out to do.
And really, you didn't do
anything except take care of yourself.
People need to take care of themselves.
And they don't.
And again, drink a bottle of water,
take a walk, be on time to work.
Don't be five minutes late to work.
Just try a few small baby steps.
Because what happens is you get
into that New Year's resolution mindset.
You know, every day is New Year's resolution.
Today's the day.
I'm going to stop doing A, B, C, D.
I'm going to start.
Doing E, F, G, H.
And you get to A, B, and you're done.
And now you failed.
And now you feel ashamed.
You feel disappointed.
So you turn on Netflix, get a
bag of chips, and start all over.
Pack it in.
That's right.
Pack it, okay?
And it's really not that complicated.
You know, figure out what you can do.
It's not rocket science.
You don't need to do it all in a day.
Again, you didn't get here overnight.
You're not going to get out of it overnight.
Start small.
Just set the alarm.
Get out of bed.
Be on time to work, if nothing else.
But you start small.
And when you finish the day and you've
done what you said you were going to do,
go sit in a chair
and get quiet and think about,
I just did what I
said I was going to do.
Do you know how many times we set out
to do something in the course of a day
and we don't ever do it?
More often.
That's right.
A lot of the times we do stuff.
And do you know how often you sit
down and think about what you accomplished today
when you set out to accomplish something?
And then you did?
How often you sit down with yourself and sort
of take it in that today was a good day?
Because that's what it is.
You know, every day is a new day.
And every new day is the first
day of the rest of your life.
And you don't have to do it all today.
So small baby steps.
Every situation is unique.
What is your Achilles heel?
Be able to get really honest with yourself.
Is it sugar?
Is it vodka?
Is it marijuana?
Is it abuse of the dog?
Is it a bad marriage?
Are you mean to people?
You've got to get really clear
with yourself and be honest with yourself.
And then sit down and go,
Okay, today I'm going to
say hello to everybody and smile.
And that's it.
And you know what?
At the end of the day, you'll feel better.